# Daniel Baldassare, PhD

daniel.baldassare@utah.edu linkedin.com/in/dbaldassare99/

Climate scientist with over 7 years of professional and research experience in atmospheric science, climate adaptation planning, remote sensing, machine learning, and engineering. Skilled manager having overseen teams as large as 30 while delivering on complex projects.

# **Education**

- **Doctor of Philosophy PhD, Atmospheric Science**, *University of Utah*, 2021 2024
- Master of Science MS, Atmospheric Science University of Nevada, Reno, 2019 2020
- **Bachelor of Science BS, Geophysics** *University of California, Davis*, 2011 2015

# **Experience**

## • Climate Scientist (Contract)

Sierra Institute for Community and Environment, April 2024 - Present

- o Wrote the NEPA Climate Report for a large restoration project in the Plumas NF.
- o Processed raw climate model outputs into actionable climate risk insights.

### Climate Dynamics Research Assistant

University of Utah, Jan 2022 - May 2024

- Developed improved projections of impactful climate features using statistical, physical, and numerical methods.
- o Processed terabytes of climate data to identify and analyze physical phenomena.

# Mechanical Engineering Research Assistant

University of Utah, Jan 2021 - Dec 2021

- Designed and implemented machine learning and physics-based wind and flux measurement devices utilizing drone thermal imagery.
- o Established a data pipeline for processing raw infrared data to derive wind speed.

#### Director

Castine Yacht Club, Jun 2020 - Sep 2021 (Seasonal)

- o Managed operations, facilities, hiring, and staff at a yacht club in Maine.
- Reported to board of directors and oversaw finances and long-term planning.

### Physics Research Assistant

University of Nevada, Reno, Aug 2019 - Dec 2020

 Processed multiple terabyte-scale atmospheric datasets using Python to produce novel insights into surface level meteorology.

### • Engineering Research Technician

University of California, Davis, Jun 2018 - Aug 2019

#### Geophysics Research Assistant

University of California, Davis, Sep 2014 - Sep 2015